we need to
write a method that takes a string as an
argument
if the string argument is greater than
10 characters
we want to return a new string with all
the characters uppercase
if the string argument has 10 characters
or less
we want to return the original string so
we'll call our method
caps and name the parameter
string and we can use a simple
if else conditional statement to achieve
this functionality
as the condition for our if statement
we'll examine the length of the string
we'll use the string length method to
return the length of the string
and we'll compare that length to the
integer 10.
this comparison will return either true
or false
if the comparison returns true and the
string's length is greater than 10
we want to return an uppercase version
of that string
and we can do that by using the string
up case method
if ruby does not execute this first
branch of our if statement
then we know our conditional return
false
and our string is less than or equal to
10 characters
so we'll just return the original string
let's invoke our caps method and we'll
pass
it one string argument with less than 10
characters
and another with more than 10 characters
and i'm going to output the return value
of each of these method invocations
we expect that the first method
invocation will return the original
string
and the second method invocation will
return the name with all uppercase
letters
so we'll run our file
and we see the result we expected